# 你看這條狗 胖成這樣子啦 不知道是不是
Look at this puppy! Ridiculously fat! I wonder if he's...
# 別跑 別跑 別跑
Stay here, stay here, stay here!
# 這狗 它的毛怎麼全部是拱起來的
This puppy, why is his hair all curling up?
# 它也不是很胖啊 哈
He's not really that fat, ha!
# 就是毛全部豎起來的 這個毛
It's just that the hair is all standing up, the hair.
# 爆炸頭一樣 爆炸型的哦
It's like afro style, afro style you know.
# 不可以打架
No fighting!
# 它的我好多哇 它的毛
He has a lot of hair, a lot.
# 這條那麼標亮 這條
He's so pretty, this puppy.
# 一臉懵逼
He looks perplexed.
# 看一下那個花的
Let's have a look at the tinted ones.
# 還有花的(狗子)
There are tinted (puppies) too.
# 它自己會走
They can walk by themselves.
# 不用我們管
We don't need to take care of them.
# 眼睛睜開了 看到沒
The eyes have already opened, see?
# 這條 這條 這條金紅色的
This one, this one, this one is golden red.
# 它這種顏色 這黑狗生出這個顏色出來
This colour, how can this black dog have a puppy of this colour?
# 好啦 叫那麼大聲
Enough! You're yelping so loudly.
# 坐下來
Sit!
# 它們都在吃奶
They're all sucking milk.
# 這條花的 你看 這條花的
This is tinted. Look! This is a tinted puppy.
# 有點瘦 可能是下崽 下得太多啦
It's a bit skinny. Perhaps there are too many puppies in this litter.
# 下了6只
There are six.
# 小狗~
Puppie~
# 它不理我
No response.
# 給你按摩
Give you a massage.
# 不打擾它們吃奶啦
I'd better not disturb their meal time.
# 大家好 現在這十幾畝 大幾畝的包菜呀
Hi everyone! These dozens, dozens of mu of cabbages here (1 mu = 667 meter square),
# 額 兄弟都把它送給我哦
eh, my buddy gives them all to me.
# 它這個好小哇 好看
This one is really tiny, look!
# 有些很小的 有些都還沒長大
Some are really small, some have not even grown up.
# 今年的行情不好 他說
The sale this year is not that good, he said.
# 所以他就全部送給我們啦
So he gives all these to us.
# 有些 裂開的我們就可以拿去餵豬
Some are, cracked, and can be given to the pigs.
# 像農戶
Like the farmers,
# 農戶他們也經常來這裡砍 也砍了些
the farmers are also coming here quite often. And they have taken some too.
# 你看 這個就很靚啊 這種
Look! This is really beautiful, this one.
# 剛剛包起來的
It has just grown up.
# 上次我割了批走
I've already taken a batch last time,
# 割了五六千斤
with almost three tones.
# 你看 現在都爆掉啦
Look! They're already cracked.
# 這個就可以吃的 這個
This one is edible, this one.
# 你看 這樣的包菜 很靚的哦
Look! Such a cabbage, is really beautiful!
# 我們把這個裝一下
Let's put it here.
# 把到靚的來割
We take the beautiful ones.
# 下次把麵包車開過來
I'll come with my van next time,
# 開過來把這些菜全部裝回去
then I can take all these cabbages with me,
# 拿來餵小豬
to feed the piggies.
# 直接割完的(註︰他想說甚麼？)
I'll take every single one.
# 你看 這樣的小包菜
Look! This is a small cabbage,
# 小包菜很靚的哦 這些小包菜
these small cabbages are really beautiful.
# 你看 剛剛好煮一餐
Look! It's a perfect size for a meal.
# 這邊也有
This side too.
# 你看 這邊也有
Look! There are some more on this side.
# 不要那麼大的
We don't want the big ones.
# 就這樣小的就可以
This kind of small ones are good enough.
# 這麼小的更好吃
These small ones taste even better,
# 這樣小嫩
cuz they're more tender.
# 越小越嫩
The smaller, the more tender
# 這個就
And this one,
# 還會大的
can still grow.
# 但是這樣子更嫩 更好吃
But now it's more tender, and tastes better.
# 吃小一點的 不要那麼大的
We take the smaller ones, not the big ones.
# 這個可以啦
It's alright now.
# 這3個小包菜
These three small cabbages
# 一個煮一餐
One for one meal
# 你看 這個包菜很靚的哦 你看
Look! This cabbage is really beautiful. look!
# 可以做成手撕包菜 這就樣一片片把它撕下來
It can be made into hand shredded cabbage. Just peel it piece by piece,
# 然後再來炒 就是手撕包菜
and then fry it. And it is hand shredded cabbage.
# 砍多一點 反正都還很多
Why don't we get more? There are still a lot.
# 那麼靚的
Beautiful!
# 這個有點爛的就要把它撕掉
This one is a bit rotten. Let me peel it.
# 這葉子有點爛 撕掉就好啦
The leaves are a bit rotten. Take them away and it'll be fine.
# 你看 這葉子撕掉就
Look! After taking away the leaves,
# 很靚啊
it's so beautiful.
# 哇 就跟超市賣的一樣的
Wa! It's just like those in the supermarket.
# 啊 你看 這樣就可以啦
Ah! Look! It's alright now!
# 摘了那麼一點(點) 好 夠啦 夠啦 夠啦
We have just a tiny little bit here. Alright! It's enough, enough, enough.